It was around here somewhere.
كانت في مكان ما هنا.
-Yeong-ji.
- "يونغ جي".
You have until the end of today.
لديك مهلة حتى نهاية اليوم.
If you fail, I can't promise
إن فشلت فلا يمكنني أن أعدك
your shop or that girl will be safe.
أن متجرك أو تلك الفتاة سيكونان بأمان.
I was only…
كنتُ فقط…
I didn't see a thing.
لم أر شيئًا.
I was only digging for herbs.
كنت أبحث عن الأعشاب فقط.
I honestly didn't see a thing,
لم أر شيئًا حقًا،
so please carry on with whatever you were doing.
لذا أرجوك أن تتابعي ما كنت تفعلينه.
It's dangerous to be out here though.
لكن وجودك هنا خطير أيضًا.
Hear that sound?
هل تسمعين ذلك الصوت؟
His Majesty is out on a royal hunt.
صاحب الجلالة في رحلة صيد ملكي.
Out here you may be mistaken for a beast and be shot at.
بوجودك هنا قد يظنون أنك وحش ويطلقون السهام عليك.
Come with me. I'll escort you out of these woods.
تعالي معي، سأُرافقك للخروج من هذه الغابة.
Leave. I don't need your help.
ارحل، لا أحتاج إلى مساعدتك.
Come on. Don't be like that
كفاك، لا تتصرفي هكذا
and put your clothes back on.
وأعيدي ارتداء ملابسك.
If you don't want to,
إن كنت لا تريدين ذلك،
I guess you may choose not to.
أظنّ أنك قد تختارين عدم القيام بذلك.
Are you…
هل أنت…
on the run?
هاربة؟
Are you a court maid…
هل أنت خادمة بلاط؟
or--
أو…
That was more than I expected from a woman.
كان هذا أكثر مما توقعته من امرأة.
However,
لكن…
this blade is quite sharp.
هذا النصل حادّ جدًا.
Damn, I know he went this way.
تبًا، أعرف أنه ذهب من هنا.
Darn it.
اللعنة.
My bow is rather accurate today.
قوسي دقيق إلى حد ما اليوم.
Could he have seen my face?
هل يمكن أن يكون قد رأى وجهي؟
Whatever.
لا يهمّ.
Wait. Isn't that…
مهلًا، أليس ذلك…
Follow me.
اتبعيني.
It'll be the end if we get caught.
سينتهي أمرنا إذا أمسكوا بنا.
For you and also for me.
من أجلك ومن أجلي أيضًا.
What is this?
ما هذا؟
What on earth is going on?
ما الذي يجري؟
That way.
من هنا.
Identify yourselves!
عرّفا عن نفسيكما!
-Get them! -Yes, sir!
- أمسكوا بهما! - أمرك، سيدي!
Giddyap.
انطلق.
Over there!
هناك!
What now?
ماذا الآن؟
-Jump. -What?
- اقفز. - ماذا؟
EPISODE 3
"الحلقة الثالثة"
MERCHANT
"تاجر"
What is it that you've been cherishing?
ما الذي كنت توليه كثيرًا من الاهتمام؟
One might think it's your beloved.
قد يظنّ المرء أنها محبوبتك.
It's nothing.
لا شيء.
Come on, my lord.
كفاك يا سيدي.
What's of value should be shared, Lord Jaeun.
يجب أن نتشارك كل ما له قيمة أيها اللورد "جايون".
But this is an ordinary brush.
لكن هذه فرشاة عادية.
It's too big for a fine writing brush and too small for a middle-sized one.
إنها كبيرة جدًا بالنسبة لفرشاة كتابة جميلة وصغيرة جدًا بالنسبة لواحدة متوسطة الحجم.
Give it here. It's for someone I treasure.
أعطني إياها، إنها لشخص أُقدّره جدًا.
The brush-maker must not have done a good job.
لا بد أن صانع الفرشاة لم يقم بعمل جيد.
It's not of an adequate size for a man to use.
إنها ليست بالحجم المناسب ليستخدمها رجل.
We must be here.
لا بد أننا وصلنا.
The Crown Prince has vanished?
هل اختفى وليّ العهد؟
He ran to the woods near the valley
هرب إلى الغابة قرب الوادي
and then disappeared.
ثم اختفى.
-Goodness. -My gosh. What on earth?
- يا للهول. - يا للهول، ما هذا؟
Until I deliver the news to His Majesty, man your posts.
ابقوا في مواقعكم إلى أن أُوصل الخبر إلى جلالته.
Yes, sir.
حسنًا يا سيدي.
Could His Royal Highness have taken advantage of the situation and ran off?
هل يُعقل أن يكون صاحب السموّ قد استغلّ الوضع وهرب؟
Do you not know who you serve?
ألا تعرف من تخدم؟
He would never go anywhere without telling us first.
لن يذهب إلى أي مكان من دون أن يخبرنا أولًا.
Something must have happened to him.
لا بد أن شيئًا قد حدث له.
Either that, or he must be in a predicament.
إما هذا، أو أنه وقع في مأزق.
-Goodness. -You.
- يا للهول. - أنت.
-Follow me. -Yes, sir.
- اتبعني. - حاضر يا سيدي.
-Hold on. -Yes?
- انتظر. - ماذا؟
What on earth is happening?
ماذا يحدث؟
Take it just in case.
خُذ هذه تحسّبًا لأي طارئ.
We must find the Crown Prince before anyone else does.
يجب أن نجد وليّ العهد قبل أي شخص آخر.
Please do not worry.
لا تقلقي رجاءً.
What's with the ruckus?
لم كل هذه الجلبة؟
Lord Jaeun!
اللورد "جايون"!
I heard you went to Mokcheon on business for the Ministry of Rites.
سمعت أنك ذهبت إلى "موكتشيون" للقيام بعمل يخصّ وزارة الشعائر.
It ended faster than expected.
انتهى بسرعة أكبر مما توقعت.
Anyway, is something the matter?
على أي حال، هل هناك خطب ما؟
Where's His Royal Highness?
أين صاحب السموّ الملكي؟
Well…
في الحقيقة…
I'll fill you in later. Later!
سأُخبرك لاحقًا، في وقت لاحق!
I'll fill you in later!
سأُخبرك لاحقًا!
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
Could…
هل يمكن…
Could she be dead?
هل يمكن أن تكون قد ماتت؟
Father!
أبي!
On the day I was born,
في اليوم الذي وُلدت فيه،
what did my father say?
ماذا قال أبي؟
My sweet boy.
ابني الحبيب.
Did he also agree
هل اتفق أيضًا
with those who wanted to terminate my life?
مع أولئك الذين أرادوا إنهاء حياتي؟
That a girl was of no need and should be killed?
لا حاجة إلى وجود فتاة ويجب قتلها؟
Is that what he said?
هل هذا ما قاله؟
The order came from the King.
أتى الأمر من الملك.
His Majesty couldn't have gone against his father, the preceding King.
ما كان يمكن لجلالته أن يعارض أمر والده، الملك السابق.
Are you all right, Your Highness?
هل أنت بخير سموّك؟
Hyun?
"هيون"؟
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السموّ الملكي.
He will soon be caught now that Commander Yoon went after him.
سيُلقى القبض عليه قريبًا بما أن القائد "يون" لحق به.
-But-- -Are you sure you're all right?
- لكن… - هل أنت واثق من أنك بخير؟
Were you harmed?
هل تأذّيت؟
Hold on. How on earth are you here, Hyun?
مهلًا، كيف أتيت إلى هنا يا "هيون"؟
We must head out of the woods since it's not safe here.
يجب أن نخرج من الغابة بما أن المكان غير آمن هنا.
Soldiers must be informed of what happened.
يجب إعلام الجنود بما حدث.
But…
لكن…
I'll need a minute, Hyun.
سأحتاج إلى بعض الوقت يا "هيون".
I didn't notice before, but what happened to your attire?
لم أُلاحظ هذا من قبل، لكن ماذا حدث لملابسك؟
Your Royal Highness!
يا صاحب السموّ الملكي!
Are you all right?
هل أنت بخير؟
You should change into these first.
يجب أن ترتدي هذه الملابس أولًا.
An assassin?
قاتل مأجور؟
An assassin attacked the Crown Prince?
قاتل مأجور هاجم وليّ العهد؟
Yes, Commander Yoon went after him,
نعم، ذهب القائد "يون" لملاحقته،
so we'll soon know of his identity.
لذا سنعرف هويته قريبًا.
Why are you still standing here? Go after the assassin!
لماذا ما زلتم تقفون هنا؟ الحقوا بالقاتل!
-Yes, sir!
- أمرك، سيدي!
Are you sure you were unharmed?
هل أنت متأكد من أنك لم تتأذّ؟
That was a close call.
كان ذلك وشيكًا.
Your Majesty, we should return to the palace.
جلالتك، يجب أن نعود إلى القصر.
It seems as though danger lurks in these woods.
يبدو أن الخطر يختبئ في هذه الغابة.
I will command the royal carriage to be ready--
سآمر أن تكون العربة الملكية جاهزة…
No one should leave the royal hunting site.
يجب ألّا يغادر أحد موقع رحلة الصيد الملكي.
Explain yourself, Left State Councilor.
فسّر لي الأمر يا مستشار الدولة الأيسر.
Soldiers stand guard here at the royal hunting site.
يقف الجنود للحراسة هنا في موقع الصيد الملكي.
Without help from an insider,
من دون مساعدة شخص من الداخل،
how could an assassin have made it to our vicinity?
كيف يمكن لقاتل أن يكون قد وصل إلى محيطنا؟
Are you accusing us of sneaking in an assassin?
هل تتهمنا بالسماح بدخول قاتل؟
Those who'd benefit from His Royal Highness' falling
أولئك الذين سيستفيدون من موت سموّه
are undoubtedly all gathered here.
كلّهم مجتمعون هنا بلا شك.
What?
ماذا؟
-Your Majesty. -Choose your words carefully.
- جلالتك. - اختر كلماتك بحذر.
It's why we must get to the bottom of this.
لهذا السبب يجب أن نصل إلى حقيقة الأمر.
Even if we have to burn down the whole forest,
حتى لو اضطُررنا لإحراق الغابة بأكملها،
we must figure out
علينا أن نكتشف
the identity of the assassin.
هوية القاتل المأجور.
A body most likely to be the assassin's was found near Samil Peak.
وُجدت جثة قرب قمة "ساميل" وهناك احتمال كبير أن تكون جثة القاتل.
Move the body.
انقلوا الجثة.
-Yes, sir.
- أمرك، سيدي.
Isn't he a soldier from one of the Five Central Armies?
أليس جنديًا من أحد جيوش الوسط الخمسة؟
Are you certain that this is the assassin who came after the Crown Prince?
هل أنت متأكد من أن هذا هو القاتل الذي لاحق وليّ العهد؟
From what I hear, he had been disgruntled with the Left State Councilor.
وفقًا لما سمعته، فقد كان مستاءً من مستشار الدولة الأيسر.
According to multiple sources,
وفقًا لمصادر متعددة،
he ran his mouth off while drunk, openly suggesting the idea of murdering
تكلّم بصفاقة وهو ثمل، واقترح صراحة فكرة أن يتمّ قتل
not only the Left State Councilor but also his grandson, His Royal Highness.
ليس مستشار الدولة الأيسر فقط بل حفيده أيضًا، صاحب السموّ الملكي.
Now that the threat is no longer,
بما أن التهديد لم يعُد موجودًا،
you should return to the palace, Your Majesty.
يجب أن تعود إلى القصر جلالتك.
See to it that he wasn't working for anyone.
تأكد من أنه لم يكن يعمل لصالح أحد.
Why that…
يا لها من…
This was clearly a conspiracy.
من الواضح أنها كانت مؤامرة.
The Queen's people could have arranged this for all we know.
من يدري؟ ربما دبّر أتباع الملكة هذا الأمر.
The Queen has the King wrapped around her fingers even tighter now,
تسيطر الملكة بشكل أكبر على الملك الآن،
which could lead to Prince Jehyeon threatening His Royal Highness' status!
مما قد يؤدي إلى تهديد الأمير "جيهيون" لمكانة سموّه!
Minister No!
أيها الوزير "نو"!
I only meant that it should never happen.
ما قصدته هو أنه يجب ألّا يحدث ذلك مطلقًا.
Yeong-ji!
"يونغ جي"!
Yeong-ji…
"يونغ جي"…
Is the Samgaebang physician still not back?
ألم يعُد طبيب "سامغايبانغ" بعد؟
He's not.
لم يعُد.
I only have myself to blame
لا ألوم إلا نفسي
for trusting a hack who has rumors for credentials.
على الثقة بطبيب فاشل مؤهلاته هي مجرد شائعات.
He will come back.
سوف يعود.
Physician Jung always keeps his word.
الطبيب "جونغ" يفي بوعده دائمًا.
And the rumors only reflect his medical talent.
والشائعات تعكس موهبته الطبية فقط.
Your faith in him is admirable.
ثقتك به تستحقّ الإعجاب.
I didn't realize until now how pretty you were.
لم أُدرك حتى الآن كم أنت جميلة.
Rather than killing you, how about I brand you instead?
بدلًا من قتلك، ما رأيك أن أضع علامة على وجهك؟
Get your hands…
أبعدي يديك…
off her.
عنها.
-Ji-un. -Ji-un!
- "جي أون". - "جي أون"!
Delivered as promised.
أحضرتها كما وعدت.
Your herbs.
هذه أعشابك!
I thought you would have run away.
ظننت أنك ستهرب.
Running away isn't in my books especially if there's someone to protect.
الهرب ليس من ضمن حساباتي، خاصةً إن كان هناك من يجب حمايته.
Not so fast.
ليس بهذه السرعة.
How can I trust that these herbs are the remedy?
كيف لي أن أثق أن هذه الأعشاب هي الدواء؟
You wouldn't have waited for me if you didn't have hope.
ما كنت لتنتظريني لو لم يكن لديك أمل.
Aren't I right?
ألست محقًا؟
Are you okay? Do you have a fever?
هل أنت بخير؟ هل تعانين من الحمّى؟
I'm sorry for putting you through this. Let's go home.
آسف لأنني ورطتك في هذه المشكلة، لنذهب إلى المنزل.
I hope there wasn't any trouble on your trip.
آمل أنه لم تحدث أي مشاكل في رحلتك.
You're worried about me when you're tied up?
هل أنت قلقة بشأني وأنت مقيدة؟
Worry about yourself first.
اقلقي على نفسك أولًا.
I couldn't help it, you know.
لم أستطع أن أمنع نفسي من ذلك.
I couldn't sleep after hearing about what happened at the royal hunting.
لم يغمض لي جفن بعد سماع ما حدث في رحلة الصيد الملكي.
It gives me great relief to see you in one piece.
إن رؤيتك سليمًا معافى تُشعرني براحة كبيرة.
We were blessed.
كنا محظوظين.
Prince Jehyeon was deeply concerned for his brother's safety.
كان الأمير "جيهيون" قلقًا جدًا على سلامة أخيه.
I'm truly glad the assassin was caught, brother.
أنا سعيد جدًا لأنهم قبضوا على القاتل يا أخي.
I apologize for alarming you.
أعتذر على إخافتك.
From what I hear,
حسب ما سمعته،
the Queen was also present at the royal hunting.
كانت الملكة موجودة أيضًا في رحلة الصيد الملكي.
Yes, per His Majesty's request, I--
نعم، بناءً على طلب جلالته، أنا…
A hen shouldn't cry before the rooster does.
يجب ألّا تصيح الدجاجة قبل أن يصيح الديك.
You should have known when and when not to be present.
كان يجب أن تعرفي متى تحضرين ومتى تغيبين.
I will keep that in mind, Your Majesty.
لن أنسى ذلك يا صاحبة الجلالة.
Your Royal Highness will someday lead this nation and the people.
أنت يا صاحب السموّ الملكي ستقود هذه الأمّة والشعب يومًا ما.
Please know that you must be careful at all times.
أرجو أن تحرص على توخي الحذر دائمًا.
I hope you understand what I mean.
آمل أن تفهم ما أعنيه.
I do, Grandmother.
أنا أفهمك يا جدتي.
It never ceases to amaze me
دائمًا ما تصيبني الدهشة
how disciplined those of the Crown Prince's quarters are.
بسبب الانضباط لدى العاملين في جناح وليّ العهد.
They're always exactly five steps away.
في كل الأوقات، يقفون تمامًا على بعد خمس خطوات عن بعضهم البعض.
Sometimes, it even fascinates me.
حتى إن ذلك يذهلني أحيانًا.
The future leader of this nation
القائد المستقبلي لهذه الأمّة
shouldn't let small details go by undetected.
يجب ألّا يدع التفاصيل الصغيرة تمرّ دون أن تُكشف.
And that same rule applies to business at the Crown Prince's quarters.
والقاعدة ذاتها تنطبق على العمل في جناح وليّ العهد.
Once again, I am enlightened, brother.
اكتسبت معرفة جديدة مجددًا يا أخي.
How can he be this cold to his one and only younger brother?
كيف يمكنه أن يكون بهذه القسوة تجاه أخيه الصغير الوحيد؟
One may say he brought the assassin on himself.
ربما كان يستحقّ استهدافه من قبل القاتل.
Mother, please.
أرجوك يا أمي.
I'm just saying.
هذا رأيي فحسب.
Being born first doesn't make him superior.
ولادته أولًا لا تجعله متفوقًا.
Good going, Your Royal Highness. I felt the kick from even where I was standing--
أحسنت صنعًا يا صاحب السموّ، شعرت بوقع كلماتك من مكان وقوفي…
Nothing good will come out of being at odds with the Queen.
لا خير سيأتي من خلافاتنا مع الملكة.
That has never been my intention.
لم تكن هذه نيتي قط.
It is the Queen who sees me as an eye-sore.
الملكة هي التي تنزعج من وجودي.
Could the attack really have been ordered by the Queen?
هل من الممكن أن تكون الملكة قد أمرت بتنفيذ الهجوم حقًا؟
You know how one should watch what they say within palace walls.
أنت تعلم كيف أنه على المرء أن ينتبه لكلامه داخل أسوار القصر.
Your mouth not only lets in a lot but also lets out a lot as well.
لا تأكل كثيرًا فحسب لكنك تتفوّه بالكثير من الكلام أيضًا.
That was uncalled for.
لم يكن هناك داع لهذا.
That's what you get for always crossing the line.
هذا ما تناله لتجاوزك الحدود دائمًا.
I must ask.
يجب أن أسأل.
Why did you spare the man
لماذا عفوت عن الرجل
who saw you at the royal hunting?
الذي رآك في رحلة الصيد الملكي؟
He could have been conspiring with the assassin that came after you.
من الممكن أن يكون متآمرًا مع القاتل الذي لاحقك.
He was there to dig up herbs
كان هناك ليجمع الأعشاب
which suggests that he's a herb digger or physician.
مما يوحي بأنه باحث عن الأعشاب أو طبيب.
If not, he was probably there to hunt.
وإن لم يكن كذلك فربما كان هناك ليصطاد.
I doubt he will ever step foot into the palace,
أشكّ في أنه سيدخل القصر يومًا،
which is why I chose not to complicate matters.
لذلك اخترت ألّا أُعقّد الأمور.
I see.
فهمت.
Come on.
هيا.
A court maid at the royal hunting?
خادمة بلاط في رحلة الصيد الملكي؟
She had fair skin, a delicate face, and dark brown hair.
كانت بشرتها فاتحة، ووجهها ناعم وشعرها بني داكن.
And her eyes… They were the size of this jade.
وعيناها…كانتا بحجم حجر اليشم هذا.
Her sharp gaze seemed cold in some way,
نظرتها الحادة بدت باردة بطريقة ما،
but also quite determined judging by how you look at it.
لكن قد يجد المرء فيها تصميمًا أيضًا بناءً على نظرته للأمر.
Could it be Hong-sim who works at His Majesty's chamber?
هل يمكن أن تكون "هونغ سيم" التي تعمل في مخدع صاحب الجلالة؟
Hong-sim?
"هونغ سيم"؟
It can't be her. He just said she's determined.
لا يمكن أن تكون هي، قال للتو إنها مصممة.
-Maybe Eun-yeong at the royal kitchen. -Could it be her?
- ربما "إيون يونغ" من المطبخ الملكي. - هل يمكن أن تكون هي؟
It has to be Yeon-ok who serves at the Crown Prince's quarters.
لا بد أنها "يون أوك" التي تخدم في جناح وليّ العهد.
-Hong-sim, Yeon-ok-- -As if.
- "هونغ سيم"، "يون أوك"… - كما لو أن ذلك ممكن.
-Don't be ridiculous. -It can't be her.
- لا تكوني سخيفة. - لا يمكن أن تكون هي.
-What do you mean? -He said she's determined.
- ماذا تعنين؟ - قال إنها مصممة.
Were all of those court maids at the royal hunting?
هل كانت كل خادمات البلاط أولئك في رحلة الصيد الملكي؟
Not just them. Dozens more were probably there.
ليس هنّ فقط، وربما كان هناك العشرات منهنّ أيضًا.
Is there a court maid who never made it back?
هل هناك خادمة بلاط لم تعُد قطّ؟
Someone who could have drowned.
خادمة يمكن أن تكون قد غرقت.
Don't be ridiculous.
لا تكن سخيفًا.
Anyway, why do you ask?
على أي حال، لماذا تسأل؟
Well…
في الحقيقة…
No reason.
لا يوجد سبب.
No…
لا…
Grandfather?
جدّي؟
You aren't the eldest son of the Crown Prince.
لست الابن الأكبر لوليّ العهد.
The one who should have died was you.
من كان يجب أن يموت هو أنت.
You should have died instead!
كان يجب أن تموتي عوضًا عنه!
Your Royal Highness, I thought you were in your chambers.
يا صاحب السموّ الملكي، ظننتك في غرفتك.
What are you doing out here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
Disturbance keeps finding me in my sleep.
لا أنعم مطلقًا بالنوم الهانئ.
Don't mind me
لا تكترث لأمري
and turn in.
واخلد إلى النوم.
Was it the same nightmare?
هل كان الكابوس نفسه؟
It hasn't haunted you for a while now.
لم يراودك منذ فترة.
I'll have the royal pharmacy bring you calming medication.
سأطلب من الصيدلية الملكية أن تحضر لك دواءً مهدئًا للأعصاب.
You should head back to your chambers.
يجب أن تعود إلى غرفتك.
Shush.
اصمت.
What is this about?
ما الأمر؟
-It's him. -Him? What do you mean?
- إنه هو. - هو؟ ماذا تعني؟
How is he within the palace walls?
كيف يكون موجودًا داخل جدران القصر؟
What do you plan on doing?
ما الذي تخطط لفعله؟
Wait here for me.
انتظرني هنا.
Pardon? Your Royal Highness!
عفوًا؟ يا صاحب السموّ الملكي!
Crouch down!
قرفص!
You scared the life out of me!
قد أخفتني كثيرًا!
"You scared the life out of me!"
"قد أخفتني كثيرًا!"
Anyway, did you ask around?
على أي حال، هل تحرّيت عن الأمر؟
About that court maid you saw at the royal hunting site.
بشأن خادمة البلاط التي رأيتها في موقع رحلة الصيد الملكي.
You wanted to know if she was alive.
أردت أن تعرف إن كانت حية.
I don't know. There's a high chance she wasn't a court maid after all.
لا أعرف، هناك احتمال كبير بأنها لم تكن خادمة بلاط في النهاية.
I wonder who could have made you want to visit the palace you try to avoid?
أتساءل من جعلك ترغب في زيارة القصر الذي تحاول تجنبه.
Just take this.
خُذ هذا فحسب.
That hurts!
هذا مؤلم!
You didn't have to.
لم يكن عليك فعل ذلك.
I've been dying to ask,
كنت أتوق لأسأل،
but rumor has it that you donate your earnings to the poor. Is that true?
لكن هناك إشاعة تقول إنك تتبرع بدخلك للفقراء، هل هذا صحيح؟
Says who?
من يقول ذلك؟
Enough with the nonsense and lead the way.
توقّف عن هذا الهراء واصطحبني إلى خارج القصر.
Sure. We should go before the gatekeepers change shifts.
بالطبع، يجب أن نذهب قبل أن يبدّل حراس البوابات المناوبات.
Over there!
هناك!
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
Goodness, I see you're working late even at night.
يا للعجب، أرى أنكم تعملون حتى وقت متأخر في الليل أيضًا.
Chief Gu, is that you? What brings you out at this hour?
أيها القائد "غو"، هل هذا أنت؟ لماذا خرجت في هذا الوقت؟
What brings me out? Nothing much.
لماذا خرجت؟ لا شيء مهم.
So tell me. I hope all is well at home.
أخبرني إذًا، آمل أن يكون كل شيء بخير في المنزل.
Yes, all is well.
نعم، كل شيء على ما يُرام.
Anyway, it's been a while…
على أي حال، لم أرك منذ فترة طويلة…
Please spare me.
أرجوك اصفحي عني.
I do not know anything.
لا أعرف شيئًا.
Please spare me this one time.
أرجوك أن تعفيني هذه المرة.
End it with one strike.
افعل ذلك بضربة واحدة.
It's painless that way.
لن تتألم بهذه الطريقة.
I…
أنا…
I cannot do it. I can't.
لا يمكنني فعل ذلك، لا أستطيع.
If you don't,
إن لم تفعل ذلك،
we're all as good as dead.
فسنموت جميعًا.
This is what you must do. Today and from here on out,
هذا ما يجب أن تفعله، اليوم ومن الآن فصاعدًا،
it is what you must do.
هذا ما يجب أن تفعله.
But I…
لكن أنا…
I will forever play dumb.
سأتظاهر بأنني لا أعرف شيئًا إلى الأبد.
I will never tell anyone.
لن أُخبر أحدًا أبدًا.
I will never say that Your Highness is a woman--
لن أقول أبدًا إن سموّك فتاة…
What are you doing here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
What's this?
ما هذا؟
Is that blood?
هل هذه دماء؟
The shot came from over there.
جاء السهم من هناك.
This is bad. We must leave this instant.
هذا سيئ، يجب أن نغادر حالًا.
Come on. Hurry.
هيا، بسرعة.
The only ones who know of that door are me and that boy.
الشخصان الوحيدان اللذان يعرفان ذلك الباب هما أنا وذلك الفتى.
So how could he…
فكيف أمكنه…
-Ji-un. -Ji-un!
- "جي أون". - "جي أون"!
Why haven't you turned in?
لماذا لم تخلدا إلى النوم؟
Well, that is…
في الواقع…
We'll give you some space.
سنمنحكما بعض الخصوصية.
Right.
صحيح.
How did you know to find me here?
كيف عرفت أنني هنا؟
I heard you stopped by the house.
سمعت أنك مررت بالمنزل.
When did you return to the Capital?
متى عدت إلى العاصمة؟
I only went there to see Mother.
ذهبت إلى هناك لرؤية أمي فحسب.
You should leave now.
يجب أن تغادر الآن.
I sent you to Ming because you wanted to pursue knowledge,
أرسلتك إلى "مينغ" لأنك أردت الحصول على المعرفة،
but you return with a bag full of pointless tricks.
لكنك تعود بحيل عديمة الفائدة.
They are not pointless.
ليست عديمة الفائدة.
They are skills that could save…
إنها مهارات قادرة على إنقاذ…
a person's life.
حياة إنسان.
Skills that could have saved the lives…
مهارات كان من الممكن أن تنقذ الأرواح…
of those you chose…
التي اخترت…
to harm.
أن تؤذيها.
How long will you let that day waste your life and ruin your future?
إلى متى ستدع ذلك اليوم يبدد حياتك ويدمر مستقبلك؟
How long…
إلى متى…
will you continue to disappoint me and your mother?
ستواصل تخييب أملي أنا وأمك؟
How long, you ask?
هل تسأل إلى متى؟
I will live with that memory until the day I die.
سأعيش مع تلك الذكرى حتى يوم مماتي.
The image of you slaying that innocent girl…
صورتك وأنت تذبح تلك الفتاة البريئة…
will forever…
ستظلّ تطاردني…
haunt me.
إلى الأبد.
It's all in the past.
هذا كله من الماضي.
Move on.
امض قُدمًا.
Move on?
أمضي قُدمًا؟
There was a time when I admired you.
فيما مضى، كنت أحترمك.
I wished to be like you. But that ended…
تمنيت أن أكون مثلك، لكن الأمر انتهى…
when I found out that your honor was built on injustice.
عندما اكتشفت أن شرفك مبني على الظلم.
Injustice?
ظلم؟
Your grandfather who valued integrity over everything
جدّك الذي كان يفضّل النزاهة على كل شيء
gave me a life of injustice.
منحني حياة من الظلم.
If justice means to be upright and moral
إن كانت العدالة تعني أن تكون شريفًا وأخلاقيًا
at the expense of one's own family,
على حساب عائلتك،
then it's wiser to forever reach an agreement
فمن الحكمة إذًا أن تتوصل إلى اتفاق أبدي
with injustice itself.
مع الظلم نفسه.
That…
ذلك…
That won't be me.
لن أفعل ذلك.
I won't live like you…
لن أعيش مثلك…
or Grandfather.
أو مثل جدّي.
So do not interfere with my life again.
لذا لا تتدخل في حياتي مجددًا.
Don't come back to this place either.
لا تعُد إلى هذا المكان أيضًا.
No!
لا!
-Samgaebang? -Yes.
- "سامغايبانغ"؟ - نعم.
Chief Gu who escorted him out of the palace
القائد "غو" الذي رافقه إلى خارج القصر
has been introducing the court maids to his services from time to time.
كان يسمح له بتقديم خدماته لخادمات البلاط من وقت لآخر.
Must you do this personally though?
لكن هل يجب فعلك ذلك شخصيًا؟
I could have sought him out alone.
كان بإمكاني البحث عنه وحدي.
I will see him with my own two eyes.
سأراه بعينيّ هاتين.
What if he really is Jung Seok-jo's son?
ماذا لو كان ابن "سيوك جو جونغ" حقًا؟
I will kill him.
سوف أقتله.
Do you mean it? He's the one you once had feelings for.
هل هذا قصدك؟ إنه الشابّ الذي كانت لديك مشاعر تجاهه.
How is that any of importance now?
ما أهمية ذلك الآن؟
If it really was Jung Seok-jo's son who saw me,
إذا كان ابن "سيوك جو جونغ" هو من رآني حقًا،
I must kill him…
يجب أن أقتله…
since he's my biggest threat.
بما أنه أكبر تهديد لي.
That's true.
هذا صحيح.
It kills me to tell you that our physician stepped out to tend to urgent business.
يؤسفني أن أخبركما أن طبيبنا خرج لينجز عملًا طارئًا.
I'm afraid you'll have to head home.
أخشى أن عليكما العودة إلى المنزل.
Please be back, all right?
أرجو أن تعودا، اتفقنا؟
I'm sorry about this. Please watch your step.
أنا آسف بشأن هذا، انتبها لخطواتكما رجاءً.
If you come back, I'll let him know that you deserve his extra care.
إن عدتما فسأخبره أنكما تستحقان رعايته الإضافية.
-Put in a good word for us. -Don't you worry and have a nice day!
- تحدّث بالإيجاب عنا. - لا تقلقا واستمتعا بيومكما!
Are you the scholar from the mountains who booked an appointment the other day?
هل أنت الطالب القادم من الجبال والذي حجز موعدًا منذ بضعة أيام؟
Well…
في الواقع…
Yes, that's me.
نعم، هذا أنا.
Goodness gracious. The wait was long, wasn't it?
يا للهول، كان الانتظار طويلًا، أليس كذلك؟
I'm afraid our physician had urgent business and didn't come in today.
أخشى أن طبيبنا كان لديه عمل طارئ ولم يأت اليوم.
I feel terrible since you must have traveled far.
أشعر بالأسى بما أنك أتيت من مكان بعيد.
Please follow me. You'll be able to see him at Hongwolru.
اتبعني من فضلك، ستتمكن من مقابلته في "هونغوولرو".
Hongwolru? The courtesan house?
"هونغوولرو"؟ بيت الدعارة؟
Quiet! I see you're looking for a tavern.
هدوء! أرى أنك تبحث عن حانة.
I know a good one, so let me lead the way.
أعرف واحدة جيدة، لذا دعني أرشدك.
-Maybe next time-- -Come on.
- ربما في المرة القادمة… - هيا.
-Let's get a move on it. -But--
- لننطلق إذًا. - لكن…
It's quite all right. Come on.
لا بأس، هيا.
Let's go! This way.
هيا بنا! من هنا.
Come on. There you go.
هيا، أحسنت.
-Girls! -Hello, sir!
- يا فتيات! - مرحبًا يا سيدي!
Goodness. Let me introduce you to today's guest.
يا للعجب، اسمحن لي أن أُقدّم لكنّ ضيف اليوم.
He's a hotshot scholar from the mountainous district.
إنه طالب بارز من المنطقة الجبلية.
My dear, do you have any idea how much I've missed you?
عزيزتي، هل لديك أدنى فكرة كم اشتقت إليك؟
My Lord!
سيدي!
Anyway, let's hurry inside.
على أي حال، لنسرع إلى الداخل.
-Come on. -Goodness.
- هيا. - يا للعجب.
-My Lord! -You adorable bunny.
- سيدي! - يا لك من لطيفة.
Come on.
هيا.
Oh, dear.
يا للعجب.
Jeez. Come on now.
عجبًا، هيا الآن.
All right. Where to?
حسنًا، إلى أين؟
It seems to me that our delicate Crown Prince
يبدو لي أن وليّ عهدنا الرقيق
has a weakness no one should know about.
لديه نقطة ضعف يجب ألّا يعرفها أحد.
A weakness, you say?
هل قلت نقطة ضعف؟
So, the Crown Prince seems to be hiding something,
يبدو أن وليّ العهد يخفي شيئًا،
but I can't quite put my finger on it.
لكنني لا أستطيع تحديد ما هو.
As the Royal Preceptor, you must have inside information.
بصفتك المعلّم الملكي، لا بد أن لديك معلومات من داخل محيطه.
Gosh, what would I know?
يا للهول، وما أدراني؟
Come on.
كفاك.
So hear this.
اسمعوا هذا.
During the royal hunting, I saw the Crown Prince with his hair down.
أثناء رحلة الصيد الملكي، رأيت وليّ العهد بشعر منسدل.
And what I saw was a woman like this kind over here.
وما رأيته كان امرأة تشبه هذه المرأة.
Do you have any idea how taken aback I was?
هل تتخيلون حجم دهشتي؟
Haven't you seen anything like that?
ألم تر شيئًا كهذا من قبل؟
You said that, for some reason, there's a womanly mood to him.
قلت إنه لسبب ما، يتمتع بمزاج أنثوي.
Isn't that what you told me last time?
أليس هذا ما قلته لي المرة الماضية؟
That's… Well, I was only referring to his style of writing.
كنت أُشير فقط إلى أسلوبه في الكتابة.
His elegant penmanship and delicate lines were worthy of such compliment--
خط يده الجميل وخطوطه الدقيقة كانت تستحقّ الإطراء…
Are you seriously going to keep playing dumb with me?
هل ستستمرّ حقًا في لعب دور المغفل أمامي؟
I think that's enough, Lord Changun.
أظنّ أن هذا يكفي أيها اللورد "تشانغون".
It's the last thing you want anyone to hear.
إنه آخر شيء تودّ أن يسمعه أحد.
You seemed to have had a little too much to drink.
يبدو أنك أسرفت في الشرب.
What? I had too much to drink?
ماذا؟ أسرفت في الشرب؟
Get over here.
تعال إلى هنا.
Of course.
بالطبع.
Do I seem like a drunk moron babbling nonsense to you?
هل أبدو لك كأحمق ثمل يهذي بالهراء؟
Of course not. That's not what I meant.
بالطبع لا، ليس هذا ما قصدته.
Not what you meant?
أليس هذا ما قصدته؟
I guess that I could have mistaken your words.
ربما أخطأت في فهم كلامك.
You must think nothing of me when I'm a member of the royal family.
يجب أن لا تستخفّ بي وأنا فرد من العائلة الملكية.
A member of the royal family!
فرد من العائلة الملكية!
Do I seem like a joke to you?
هل أبدو كأحمق بالنسبة لك؟
Am I a joke to you? Am I?
هل أنا أحمق بالنسبة لك؟ هل أبدو كذلك؟
Yes, I guess I could have mistaken your words.
نعم، أظنّ أنني ربما أسأت فهم كلامك.
Damn it.
اللعنة.
Get up. It's all right, so get up.
انهض، لا بأس، انهض.
Okay, let me see.
حسنًا، دعني أرى.
Let me take a look. You…
دعني أُلقي نظرة، أنت…
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
Say it again.
قُلها مجددًا.
I dare you to say it again!
أتحداك أن تقولها مجددًا!
What is going on?
ماذا يجري؟
What on earth?
ما هذا؟
What? What is it?
ماذا؟ ما الأمر؟
Would you like to play as well?
هل تودّون أن تلعبوا أيضًا؟
What's there to spectate?
إلام تنظرون؟
-Please. -Gosh, no.
- أرجوك. - يا للهول، لا.
-Please don't. -Let go of me.
- أرجوك لا تفعل ذلك. - دعني وشأني.
Let go of me!
دعني وشأني!
Damn it!
اللعنة!
Quiet.
اصمت.
You… You're…
أنت…
How dare you.
كيف تجرؤ؟
Haven't we met?
ألم نلتق من قبل؟
I mean, at the royal hunting site.
أقصد في موقع رحلة الصيد الملكي.
The royal hunting site?
موقع رحلة الصيد الملكي؟
But from what I recall, you were definitely a woman.
لكن حسب ما أتذكّر، كنت امرأة بالتأكيد.
No, wait.
لا، مهلًا.
You can't go out there yet.
لا يمكنك الخروج إلى هناك الآن.
Don't let my saving you go to waste.
لا تدع إنقاذي لك يضيع سدى.
Who saved whom, you say?
ما الذي تقوله؟ من أنقذت؟
Haven't you heard the rumors?
ألم تسمع الشائعات؟
He's known as the madman.
يُعرف باسم "المجنون".
It's always best to walk around the turd.
من الأفضل دائمًا الابتعاد عن الحمقى.
Hey, hang on!
مهلًا، انتظر!
We should keep having our fun.
يجب أن نستمرّ في الاستمتاع بوقتنا.
All right, let's go.
حسنًا، هيا بنا.
Let's party.
لنحتفل.
So here's where we meet, Uncle.
إذًا التقينا هنا يا عمّي.
Look who it is.
انظروا من هنا.
What brings His Royal Highness here?
ما الذي جاء بسموّه الملكي إلى هنا؟
Your Royal Highness!
يا صاحب السموّ الملكي!
I see you're here too, Royal Preceptor.
أرى أنك هنا أيضًا أيها المعلّم الملكي.
A royal preceptor
معلّم ملكي
having drinks in the day with a member of the royal family?
يحتسي الخمر في النهار مع فرد من العائلة الملكية؟
How commendable.
كم هذا جدير بالثناء.
Well, this isn't what it seems.
حسنًا، ليس الأمر كما يبدو عليه.
You and that temper of yours.
يا لطبعك الحاد هذا.
From what I recall, His Majesty warned you not to assault others
حسب ما أتذكّر، حذّرك جلالة الملك من الاعتداء على الآخرين
by abusing your power and status.
من خلال إساءة استخدام سلطتك ومكانتك الاجتماعية.
Pardon?
عفوًا؟
But it wasn't some random assault.
لكنه لم يكن اعتداءً عشوائيًا.
This man insulted the royal family
هذا الرجل أهان العائلة الملكية
and all I did was discipline him.
وكل ما فعلته هو تأديبه.
You disciplined him?
هل أدبته؟
I'll keep this affair out of His Majesty's ears.
لن أُخبر جلالته بهذا الأمر.
He's been waiting to scold you.
إنه ينتظر كي يوبخك.
The same goes for the Queen Dowager too.
الأمر نفسه ينطبق على الملكة الأرملة أيضًا.
That being said, what brings you here of all places?
على ذكر ذلك، ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا من بين كل الأماكن؟
There are more than enough women at the palace.
ثمة الكثير من النساء في القصر.
I'm not of your kind, Uncle.
لست من أمثالك يا عمّي.
I'm only here to meet a friend.
أنا هنا لمقابلة صديق فقط.
A friend?
صديق؟
I'm not in the mood for drinks anymore, so we should leave.
لم أعُد في مزاج مناسب للشرب، لذا علينا أن نغادر.
That reminds me.
قد تذكرت.
I saw improvement…
رأيتُ تحسّنًا…
in your archery skills.
في مهاراتك في الرماية.
Pardon?
عفوًا؟
If you wish to be beheaded
إذا كنت تريد أن يُقطع رأسك
as the man behind the assassination attempt,
بصفتك الرجل المسؤول عن محاولة الاغتيال،
keep being cheeky.
فاستمرّ في التصرف بوقاحة.
Let's go.
هيا بنا.
-Physician Jung! -Physician Jung, it's been so long.
- أيها الطبيب "جونغ"! - أيها الطبيب "جونغ"، مرّ وقت طويل.
-It worked like a charm. -We've been waiting.
- نجح الأمر كالسحر. - كنا ننتظر.
It's been too long.
قد تأخرت كثيرًا.
Are you free today? I'd like this side done too.
هل أنت متفرّغ اليوم؟ أريد أن نعالج هذا الجانب أيضًا.
-Please? -Hold on a second.
- أرجوك. - مهلًا لحظة.
Now's not the time.
ليس الآن بالوقت المناسب.
Later.
لاحقًا.
So, what was it that you were about to say?
إذًا، ما الذي كنت على وشك أن تقوله؟
-Pardon? -The royal hunting site?
- عفوًا؟ - موقع رحلة الصيد الملكي؟
I doubt anyone who isn't a soldier
أشكّ أن أي أحد غير الجنود
or part of the royal family could have been there.
أو أفراد العائلة الملكية يمكن أن يكون موجودًا هناك.
Yes… Yes, of course. I wasn't there.
نعم، بالطبع، لم أكن هناك.
Only someone with a death wish would have landed himself there.
وحده من يتمنى الموت سيذهب إلى هناك.
What is your name?
ما اسمك؟
My name is Jung Ji-un.
اسمي "جي أون جونغ".
When did you return from Ming?
متى عُدت من "مينغ"؟
Do you remember me?
هل تتذكرني؟
Yes.
نعم.
Bits and pieces are coming together.
بدأت أتذكّر بعض الأمور.
Many years ago, you came to me to introduce yourself.
قبل سنوات عديدة، جئت إليّ لتعرّفني بنفسك.
I'm honored, Your Royal Highness.
هذا شرف لي يا صاحب السموّ.
Never did I think you were His Royal Highness though.
لكنني لم أظنّ قطّ أنك صاحب السموّ.
Please forgive my impudence.
أرجو أن تسامحني على وقاحتي.
Fine. Consider yourself forgiven.
حسنًا، اعتبرني سامحتك.
Thank you, Your Royal Highness.
شكرًا لك يا صاحب السموّ.
Just as you were all those years ago,
تمامًا كما كنت قبل كل تلك السنوات،
you are still as kind and generous.
ما زلت لطيفًا وكريمًا.
However,
لكن…
if I ever see you again,
إن رأيتك مجددًا،
I will withdraw…
فسأتراجع…
my forgiveness.
عن مغفرتي.
Keep what I said in mind.
تذكّر ما قلته.
Of course.
بالطبع.
Of course, Your Royal Highness.
بالطبع يا صاحب السموّ.
Your… Your Royal Highness! Jeez.
يا صاحب السموّ الملكي! يا للهول.
Your Royal Highness!
يا صاحب السموّ الملكي!
Is it him? Is it?
هل هذا هو؟
Follow me.
اتبعيني.
Quiet.
اصمت.
Court Lady Kim ordered me to help you to bed.
أمرتني سيدة البلاط "كيم" بمساعدتك في الخلود إلى النوم.
I'm fine, so turn in already.
أنا بخير، لذا عُد إلى فراشك حالًا.
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
حسنًا يا صاحب السموّ الملكي.
Can you afford to let him live?
هل يمكنك تحمّل تبعات إبقائه حيًا؟
Being Jung Seok-jo's son
بما أنه ابن "سيوك جو جونغ"
makes him dangerous as you stated.
فهذا يجعله خطيرًا كما قلت.
He's also someone who knows you before you claimed this identity.
كما أنه رجل يعرفك قبل أن تزعم هويتك هذه.
If he figures it out--
إذا اكتشف الأمر…
That won't happen…
لن يحدث ذلك…
for he will not
لأنه…
show himself to me again.
لن يُظهر نفسه أمامي مجددًا.
Besides, you saw for yourself.
كما أنك رأيت بنفسك.
He grew up to be a pathetic excuse for a man.
كبر ليصبح رجلًا مثيرًا للشفقة.
However, he's the son of the man who slew the young prince.
لكنه ابن الرجل الذي ذبح الأمير الشابّ.
It's exactly why… I can't complicate things.
لهذا السبب بالضبط لا أستطيع تعقيد الأمور.
Even if we do run into each other again,
حتى لو التقينا مجددًا،
he won't have any more doubts.
فلن تراوده أي شكوك أخرى.
How so?
كيف ذلك؟
Anyone who knows Dam-i…
كل من يعرف "دامي"…
would never think that the Crown Prince
لن يتخيل أبدًا أن وليّ العهد
could ever be a girl.
من الممكن أن يكون فتاة.
-You called for me, Lord? -Have a seat.
- هل استدعيتني أيها اللورد؟ - اجلس.
Is the man named Jung Ji-un your son?
هل الرجل الذي يُدعى "جي أون جونغ" هو ابنك؟
Rumor has it that he's a skilled acupuncturist.
يُشاع أنه بارع في العلاج بالوخز بالإبر.
I heard he saved the Vice Minister of Rites of Ming.
سمعت أنه أنقذ نائب وزير الشعائر في "مينغ".
It's true that he studied in Ming,
صحيح أنه درس في "مينغ"،
but I'm not aware of his actions there.
لكنني لا أعرف ماذا فعل هناك.
The envoy from Ming will soon visit.
ستزورنا البعثة من "مينغ" قريبًا.
I hear the Vice Minister of Rites will also be among them.
وقد سمعت أن نائب وزير الشعائر سيكون من ضمنها أيضًا.
It would be of great assistance
سيكون من المفيد جدًا
if your son could serve the Crown Prince during the visit.
إن كان بإمكان ابنك أن يخدم وليّ العهد أثناء الزيارة.
Forgive my actions from the other day.
اغفر لي أفعالي في ذلك اليوم.
It was uncalled for.
لم يكن هناك داع لذلك.
You shouldn't apologize to me
يجب ألّا تعتذري إليّ
but to the girl who you threatened to have branded.
بل إلى الفتاة التي هددتها بأن تحفري علامة على وجهها.
Is she important to you?
هل هي مهمة بالنسبة لك؟
I only thought she was a mere helper.
ظننت أنها مجرد مساعدة.
So?
إذًا؟
Is that why you thought she could be mistreated?
ألهذا السبب ظننت أنه يمكن إساءة معاملتها؟
Mistreated in the form of
إساءة معاملة على شكل حفر علامة
branding the face of an innocent?
على وجه فتاة بريئة؟
Fine. I'll apologize to her as well.
حسنًا، سأعتذر إليها كذلك.
Since you're here, if it's all right with you,
بما أنك هنا، إن كنت لا تمانع،
I'd like to suggest you stay for tea.
أودّ أن أقترح أن تبقى لاحتساء الشاي.
What on earth?
ما هذا؟
Now I checked your face is well recovered,
بما أنني تحققت من أن وجهك شُفي تمامًا،
so I'll trust that you keep your word.
لذا سأثق بأنك ستفين بوعدك.
Wait!
مهلًا!
What now? Is there more you wish to say?
ماذا الآن؟ هل هناك ما تودّين قوله بعد؟
I'm So-eun.
أنا "سو إيون".
Shin So-eun.
"سو إيون شين".
Remember the name.
تذكّر الاسم.
What on earth are you doing?
ماذا تفعلون؟
Why are you doing this?
لماذا تفعلون هذا؟
No, please don't!
لا، أرجوكم لا تفعلوا هذا!
-Don't do this! -Look here!
- لا تفعلوا هذا! - انظر هنا!
-Please-- -Move!
- أرجوك… - ابتعد!
-Jil-geum! -Yeong-ji…
- "جيل غيوم"! - "يونغ جي"…
Jil-geum!
"جيل غيوم"!
What is the meaning of this?
ما معنى هذا؟
Ji-un!
"جي أون"!
-There must be a misunderstanding. Let-- -Seize them!
- لا بد أن هناك سوء تفاهم، دعني… - اقبضوا عليهم!
What… What are you saying?
ماذا؟ ماذا تقول؟
What is this?
ما هذا؟
-Ji-un. -Take them!
- "جي أون". - خذوهم!
Jil-geum! Yeong-ji!
"جيل غيوم"، "يونغ جي"!
Arrest them all.
اعتقلوهم جميعًا.
-Ji-un! -I demand a reason!
- "جي أون"! - أطلب منكم سببًا!
Why are you doing this?
لماذا تفعلون هذا؟
-What-- -Ji-un!
- ماذا… - "جي أون"!
-Come on. -Don't struggle!
- هيا. - لا تقاوم!
My name is Jung Ji-un.
اسمي "جي أون جونغ".
There's no need to be alarmed.
لا داعي للقلق.
Go ahead. I'm sure it'll fit your grip perfectly.
تفضّل، أنا متأكد أنها ستناسب قبضتك تمامًا.
Is that so?
حقًا؟
It's as I said.
كما قلت.
It's me, not you, who knows what's best for you.
أنا من أعرف ما هو الأفضل لك وليس أنت.
Your Royal Highness.
يا صاحب السموّ الملكي.
It is time for your lecture.
حان وقت محاضرتك.
Oh, is it time already?
هل حان الوقت بهذه السرعة؟
I'm afraid
أخشى…
I must get going.
أنني يجب أن أذهب.
A new lecturer starts today.
سيبدأ معلّم جديد اليوم.
I hear one of your preceptors resigned.
سمعت أن أحد معلّميك استقال.
I'm worried as to the frequent swap in tutors.
أنا قلق بشأن الاستبدال المتكرر للمعلّمين.
Tell me about it.
أعرف هذا.
There's no talent within the royal court.
لا توجد مواهب في البلاط الملكي.
Well, anyway…
حسنًا، على أي حال…
thank you for the gift.
شكرًا لك على الهدية.
So tell me about my new lecturer.
إذًا حدّثني عن معلّمي الجديد.
All I heard is that he's a young talent who caught
كل ما سمعته هو أنه شابّ موهوب
Lord Sangheon's attention from early on.
لفت انتباه اللورد "سانغهيون" منذ البداية.
We'll see how long this one lasts.
سنرى إلى متى سيصمد هذا.
The Crown Prince shall now enter.
يدخل وليّ العهد الآن.
I hear you come with glorious recommendations.
سمعت أنك جئت بتوصيات مجيدة.
I look forward to…
أتطلع إلى…
I will be your tutor starting from today. I am Royal Tutor Jung Ji-un.
سأكون معلّمك بدءًا من اليوم، أنا المعلّم الملكي "جي أون جونغ".
But you…
لكن أنت…
Wouldn't this be a problem?
ألن يشكّل ذلك مشكلة؟
If, by any chance, he finds out about you--
إذا صادف واكتشف أمرك…
That will never happen.
لن يحدث ذلك أبدًا.
Nothing can be easier than making a lecturer resign.
لا شيء سيكون أسهل من جعل معلّم يستقيل.
May I ask why? Why do you want to kick me out?
هل لي أن أسأل عن السبب؟ لماذا تريد طردي؟
Samgaebang?
"سامغايبانغ"؟
They mean everything to me. I will do anything to save them.
إنهما يعنيان كل شيء بالنسبة لي، سأفعل أي شيء لإنقاذهما.
A bet?
رهان؟
Get the highest mark on the upcoming exam given by all lecturers including myself.
احصل على أعلى علامة في الاختبار القادم الذي يجريه كل المعلّمين بمن فيهم أنا.
Why must I agree to that?
لماذا يجب أن أُوافق على ذلك؟
I might change my mind if you offered up your life.
قد أُغيّر رأيي إذا راهنت بحياتك.
I will bet my life on it.
أُراهن بحياتي على ذلك.
Subtitle translation by: Hye-lim Park
ترجمة "مي جمال"